[Music]
this is software engineering radio the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at
e-r. SC radio is brought to you by the
it computer society and by It software
Magazine online at computer.org
[Music]
software SC radio has an opening for a
volunteer host to produce five episodes
per year to apply please follow the
instructions on our website at se-
radio.net Conta
hello everyone welcome to this episode
of software engineering radio Our Guest
today is Simon vitman Simon is the
founder of Seaside Seaside is focused on
monitoring securing and optimizing
third-party javascripts welcome to the
show salimon great to have you here
before we get started is there anything
else you'd like to add to your bio well
thank you so much for having me well
something I like to add is that we start
with third party scripts today but what
we want to do is basically protect the
entire like browser as an attack surface
so today that starts with thirdparty
scripts as that's where a lot of dynamic
behaviors come from but over time we
anticipate to solve client side security
as a whole let's start though with just
third party scripts and how do they
actually fit into the browser security
supply chain what is the browser
security supply chain to start when you
go to a website a lot of things happen
right but I'm going to jump a few steps
and go straight to the part where you
actually get a response from the web
server an HTML page is loaded JavaScript
CSS Etc comes along depending on your
framework there may be server side or
client side rendering but then often in
that file or in that page there is a
reference to other third party sources
third party domains those third party
domains didn't obviously get fetched so
the browser for user installed go to
this other domain and get something from
there and that something is defined by
that path that full URL you don't
necessarily know what you're actually
getting from there so you can add a hash
to that script tag to Define
specifically the hash of the file You're
Expecting but it's really up to that web
server to serve a piece of content back
so that's how these third party scripts
are being delivered to the browser of
users and that is essentially also where
the problem begins of a third party
script so day one you think you allow a
certain thing
but it has all the capabilities for
changing over time certain things are
Dynamic and even though we refer to them
assuming that they wouldn't change in
some cases they can and so in that case
it was basically a wakeup call where if
you refer to something that is dynamic
that can change the entire context can
change and so that is also what has
happened with these third party script
Texs when people refer to a third party
script that is supposed to be a chat bot
and the week after after it is actually
listening to you entering passwords then
that is something it is perfectly
technically capable of doing and that is
a problem why do we why do developers
use third party scripts to begin with
and sounds like they're pretty common in
webd like can you explain some reasons
around that so when the world moved away
from using fully serers side things like
PHP or and we're still actively in the
process on that on some things and Flash
Player and job in browsers Etc became
less common client side JavaScript so
client side fetch JavaScript became a
much more common way of dealing with
these things and so JavaScript became
supported by browsers and people then
used big JavaScript libraries to perform
certain Dynamic actions in browsers and
in the beginning this was very efficient
because when you went to 10 different
websites and they were all using that
same library because they use a third
party domain your browser would not have
to refetch it every time is there
browser side C enabled for that package
so it was a very efficient way for
loading a Javascript file that would
allow you to have a certain behavior in
a website over time this has progressed
and people have luckily started moving
away from using client side fetch
scripts for this use only with tools
like note package manager and other
registries for open source packages
becoming more common but still these
third party scripts are necessary for
certain things like analytics tools chat
Bots ad ads often there's all sorts of
these third party that we have to use if
we want to use a certain tool and there
isn't really an alternative for many of
these so any type of like chatbots tool
for instance is often a fully
dynamically fetched client side script
so there are cases you absolutely must
use third party but you said things have
gotten better with uh note package
manager as an example can you explain
that a little bit more yes so for some
of these thirdparty scripts or used to
be third party scripts it perfectly
possible to just get an npm installable
version of that that is hostable on your
own web server on your side and a good
example of this for instance was that
polyfill.io like incident that there are
definitely ways that you can self-host
polyfill it's a static package that
hasn't really changed in the last few
years so that is something that you can
rather easily install so in some cases
where people are not using a framework
that uses node or it is just easier to
add a client side script that is where
people would use something like ball.io
or cdnjs or yeah I mean there's a whole
bunch of these JavaScript CDN out there
that serve static JavaScript and most of
those you can actually get through other
means as well that are more secure okay
so get them scan them and host them if
they are static then that is the best
thing you can do and I highly Advocate
that people do that but unfortunately
you can't do that all the time and so
for tools that are captas or chat Bots
or ads where there is a certain
requirement for dynamic you may actually
require like yeah still using these
third party scripts and even in some of
these scripts that you actually can
install as a static script there are
actually calls to third party domains
still happening be it data being
extrated there which can be a normal
thing but also actual fetch is still
happening to other third parties and
that is where basically the supply chain
issue that we see on Reg like note
package manager is also very relevant to
third party scripts for more on supply
chain attacks for Registries like note
package manager I'd like to point
listeners to software engineering radio
episode 535 Dan Lauren on supply chain
attacks before we get into more details
on what developers can and should do
samon can you take an example of an
attack and walk through it you did
mention polyl as a C attack do you want
to take that example and elaborate yeah
sure so let's talk about what polyfill
did first so polyfill was created by the
financial times to support there are
many different websites as large media
companies often face they have a lot of
websites some of which they handle
themselves some of which are to agencies
So within the company there was a team
task to create a package that would
support the newer websites and the older
websites across browsers and create
uniformity and so that was the the
project initially so a you like
well-known open source contributors
start working on it and then they ended
up hosting it on a third party domain
CDN bifield doio and That Was Then given
to all these agencies to implement on
the website and so this was a very
useful piece of code and in general
people liked it because people were
moving away from Internet Explorer to
Chrome at the time so cross browser
compatibility was a big subject so this
became a very popular script eventually
some of these contributors moved to
different things in their career some of
them ended up at fastly there was sort
of change of ownership conversation
happening but it never ended up
happening a chain of ownership from the
financial time never made it to fastly
they ended up changing it to the private
ownership to one of the maintainers so
this was in February this year and then
fastly jumped on that subject and put a
blog post out to alert people of this
change and offer a mirrored version of
it essentially on their own CDN and the
same happened with cloudfare cloudfare
did the exact same thing but
unfortunately as a result nobody did it
like nobody actually took it seriously
and removed that script and change to
the like other hosted version this was a
blog post how do you even know how many
people read it and what are they
supposed to take away from it I mean
there wasn't really a good serious way
of putting this to people's attention at
the time because nothing bad had
happened there was a suspicious chain of
of ownership to a Chinese company
nothing had happened at that point okay
then fast forward a few months to the
25th of June and if you had that script
on your website at that point in time
this Chinese company made an adjustment
to the code where if a certain user
agent were to request that script they
would also get another script with it
and that was hosted on Google
analytics.com so Google analytics with
an L as an i and that would end up
redirecting you to adult content
websites and online casinos which looked
like a rather juvenile attack of course
when that happened we were one of the
first ones to notice how did you notice
it that's a good question so of course
there's a lot of websites that all of a
sudden this happened we've got a lot of
features that we monitor there's of
course outcry on social media when these
things happened we were very much in an
early beta stage at the time but we
still got the Intel to come in
essentially to take it from there and so
essentially the first time we noticed
that it took about 60 Minutes for us to
put a blog post out since because we
noticed it was rather distributed at the
time we personally bumped into it when
we went to these websites but the
interesting thing is that they made the
script only inject that malicious code
once per IP address so they made it
harder to basically understand what was
happening so that was interesting and
then of course when we noticed we made a
blog post we reached out to our PR
consult since we got it in the news and
then everybody kind of jumped on it and
for some time there was widescale chaos
but nobody was really taking action
threat feeds did not mention it anywhere
so for 30 hours everybody knew it was
bad but threat Feats were still saying
it was okay and then eventually name
cheep the regist of the domain name
jumped in and purchased the domain name
kind of back I don't think there was
actually a change of money but what they
did is They removed any of the DNS like
objects or DNS queries and as a result
that domain name was no longer
responding to anything at the time that
was on more than 490,000 websites to
this day it's still on more than 380,000
websites if namh hadn't done that this
attack would still be on today that is
what we know if you'd allow me I'd like
to explain what likely happens but the
problem is that the evidence of it is
not 100% there so word on the street is
that a life-changing amount of money was
offered to the then personal maintainer
of the polyfill.io domain name and then
person was presented a solid business
Case by a Chinese company that wanted to
use it to host CDN and all that stuff
okay so the change of ownership happens
person gets the money nothing bad
happens initially now this is a script
that's on 500,000 websites and some of
those are large news websites online HR
platforms you name it there's some
really really massive logos in there the
expectation is that between February and
June it would be kind of silly that they
would have such a high value res Source
available and do nothing with it so what
we expect in the security Community is
that based on the referral header that
was used to fetch the script because at
that time they moved away from a CDN
hosted script to an actual web server
responding depending on the referral
header and perhaps some other headers
they would actually send a malicious
payload along and pull off a much more
stealthy attack to potentially steal
information like identification
information HR information could it even
been or adjust content on news websites
or whatever it could have been anything
right and then as a result they would be
successful in that attack they would
have the data that they need and then to
blow it all up and basically kill the
story and get people to think about
other things and remove their mind from
polyfill.io as a potential thing
basically Clause the subject they would
make this incredibly noisy attack happen
in June that's what we think happened
and the reason why we think that is
because first of all by redirecting
people to adult content sites and online
casinos you're not going to make
lifechanging money so there is very
little Financial incentive to do that
because the script was able to only
inject bad things for certain user
agents and only once per IP address they
were clearly aware of the advanced of
the attack that they could pull off just
wouldn't make any sense for people to
spend that amount of money to then do
that type of a juvenile attack that is
what we think the problem is we'll never
know because nobody's keeping an eye on
their client side behaviors there is no
real good Monitoring Solutions out there
aside from what we're trying to build to
actually monitor the behavior in the
browser of a user so the fact is we'll
never know and that's the real issue
with client side security this attack
Factor has been around for a long time
but we've not really had good solutions
to it for a very long time so we don't
know how often it happens until it's a
very visible and very wides scale attack
so that's that I do have some questions
on what you mentioned about word
industry but I guess you cannot really
answer with any degree of certainty but
so the thing that I will take away from
this is that just that these attacks are
so easy to pull off right basically if
you get your hands on something that
delivers a script is in the flow of the
delivery of a script you've got it and
that could be anything from the IP range
the domain name the storage bucket or
even just have access to the open source
repo of it and if it has CI and it
deploys that scripts in actual
production eventually then there you go
we've got a malicious third party script
in your hand so yes it is very easy to
pull off there's actually a really good
blog post about this that went viral in
2018 it's called I'm harvesting credit
card numbers on your site and here's how
it's a really good blog post and
basically every word that is written
there is still possible today luckily
it's fictional so it was only a joke but
nothing that's written there is
impossible and it really shows how easy
it is to execute an attack like this
I'll put it in the show notes why has
this not been more focus on third party
scripts is that increasing now and
why now so there's definitely been a
flood of these types of incidents since
2010 and I would say it kind of peaked
before covid around 2018 2019 there was
a very like widely covered attack back
then on British Airways where again
funny enough the same kind of number
half a million people's credit cards
were stolen roughly was about 460,000
roughly but yeah people's credit cards
were stolen and that was also a third-
party script although they also managed
to get access to the actual web
infrastructure of that web server they
injected a script that would monitor for
these credit cards and they would
exfiltrate that information to a domain
name and the domain name was ba.com so a
domain name that looked as if it could
have been from bsh Airways well today we
actually own that domain name so if
people want to read up on what happened
with that incident they can go to ba.com
and they can see like actually what
happened then but it basically hasn't
gone away and I would say that kind of
the media got bored with this subject
and the security industry wasn't really
building anything for it so it was one
of those annoying situations where it
happens and there isn't really an
elegant solution to it and unfortunately
the problem is likely going to become
way larger and that's for a few things
so first things first we are doing a
better job at protecting our web
infrastructure we're putting proxies in
front of it because of cloud Flare's
incredibly generous offer of giving free
proxies to everybody or a very cheap pro
and business steer a lot of web
infrastructure is now protected so
pulling off a very simple SQL injection
attack isn't as simple as it used to be
more and more of these great tools like
socket.io are soet sorry are around and
help you protect your open source
dependencies and keep an eye on those so
they make sure that whatever you get
from npm isn't causing any trouble but
then of course the question is what
remains left what is an attack surface
that is powerful enough to pull off a
serious attack but it's currently not
really being monitored well the answer
there is the client side an npm package
installs something that is actually
allowing Dynamic fetching in the browser
of a user that could be a big problem if
people add third partyy scripts to their
website that could be a big problem and
the thing is that most websites nowadays
don't actually monitor any type of
client side Behavior at all they don't
have the tools for that in place the
tools for that are also not incredibly
accessible they are rather expensive
they're usually part of a larger
Enterprise commitment with a security
company and so therefore this has just
been a problem that's been luring in the
background and there was a lack of
solutions for it and so we took action
we recognized this issue and we decided
to do the hard thing but also the right
thing of building a service that's able
to deal with these types of attacks
thanks for that Simon though I just want
to point out at least the way I
understood that the British Airways
attacks wasn't really a third part
script right well the British Airways
attack was an interesting one so through
getting their hands on credentials of a
contractor they managed to work their
way into the internal network of Bri
Airways get their way onto one of the
web servers and then they added a third
party script that extrated this data
well or they adapted a third party
script actually to add this code or a
first party script actually to add this
code that would exfiltrate credit card
information to a domain and that was
ba.com but the reality is that this
Behavior got executed client side that's
where the bad thing happened nowadays
with tools to read through code and
analyze certain behaviors you're likely
could have spot that specific one but
then there's also many other ones like
the easy jet attack there was another
one on another airliner at the end of
2023 called Air Europa all types of
retailers all types of booking sites all
types of well basically any company that
accepts credit card information online
or has a substantial amount of traffic
going to their website and by the way
this is not as hard to pull off as
people may think if you have ads on your
website you're essentially giving a
third party the ability to sell space on
your website and guess what a ad is an
ad is often a piece of JavaScript and so
adware is another way to refer to this
Trad and the thing is that as people use
large ad providers they have done a good
job at like defining which apis Those
ads can use and which they can't but as
you start looking for higher margin ones
that are maybe less reputable providers
then that security is not always there
so the issue with third party scripts is
still a very major one and has impacted
many websites over the years essentially
as soon as JavaScript was added to
browsers so you mentioned ads and
analytics as the key source for this
requiring third party scripts on your
website I would say ads is the most easy
one to get an attack into a website or
in a wide amount like a wide amount of
websites but then other tools like
analytics chatbots Etc these are often
Industries where there are lots of small
vendors and those small vendors do not
necessarily have funds to protect
themselves very well some of these
companies can randomly cease to exist or
get Acquired and a few years later is
not necessarily clear anymore who's
keeping an eye on that script another
example I like to refer to is companies
that provide a third party script that
are not inherently very technical in its
core existence so as an example for
instance there are like influencer
marketing firms out there whose core
product is their catalog of influencers
that they represent but then they ask
you to add a little script to your
website to track the conversion the
sales that happen as a result of people
clicking through from Tik Tok to the
website well those people often they
literally get a Contractor on board to
help them build that script they build
it they make it they ship it they walk
away they may be on a retainer they may
not be on a retainer and that script now
lives in a bunch of websites and those
are the types of scripts that we see
getting exploited to most out of like
all of these other scripts I would say
analytics companies they have been
grilled on this issue and because of
these attacks happening in the past of
course they are aware that they have to
take action to make sure that they're
safe that message hasn't really made it
to every different vertical of third
party script provider so what role does
the open source Community play here what
do they do and what can they do better I
think the open source Community can help
here by making sure that whatever
features and tools they provide are
available in a format that people can
self host or people can install through
a registry like npm so that at least
there is an ability of transparency
where you can see these things so avoid
building third party host scripts avoid
using them to the furthest extent that
you can and mostly be very transparent
about the security that you have like
implemented if it must be a thirdparty
script how you seek to protect your
actual infrastructure where that script
is being hosted how you make sure that
your CI around it is safe make sure that
you own that domain for a long enough
amount of time so that it doesn't all of
a sudden become a surprising situation
when it doesn't get renewed those are
all things you can do and another thing
that the open source Community can do
that I think is kind of underappreciated
but if you're building something that
likely will end up in a third party
script at some point immediately buy the
domain and own it because if you're not
going to do it someone else is going to
take that code you wrote mirror it and
buy a domain name for it and people are
going to think that you actually own
that domain name when that isn't
necessarily the case and this is
essentially what has happened with
polyfill the open source like
contributor that built that script was
not the one that owned that script and
that of course creates a headache for
everybody right because you don't really
know like the full extent of that
person's technical ability because they
didn't write that thing they are an
entirely different third party to work
with altoe so that's another thing I
would say the open source Community can
do and then as always if you bump into a
bad script report it make noise that's
how tread feeds get their data I
personally don't think thread feeds are
the answer in 2024 because there's just
too many things happening for thre feed
providers to keep an eye on and
unfortunately thread feed providers
themselves get acquired their Engineers
leave like any business there's rotation
happening over the years and their
quality is not guaranteed and the
security World tends to rely too heavily
on thread feed providers to tell them
when something is bad and when something
needs to be
stopped that is another thing that I
would say we need to start pushing back
against we cannot get away with buying
security products that are basically a
wrapper around a third party tread feed
that you can get either for free or that
is just so commonly used that by the
time it makes it onto the tread feed the
attacker knows and they've moved on to a
different attack to Loop it back to that
polyfill incident it took about 30 hours
for that script to be added to a tread
feed and that is really unacceptable 30
hours of a malicious script that could
have done anything from mining crypto in
browsers stealing people sensitive
information 30 hours of the RO World
knowing that it's bad of it literally
being on news websites before tread feed
added it is not good enough is there any
relation to browser plugins and third
party scripts in terms of mechanisms or
security policies Etc yes for sure so
under Manifesto of like the Google
Chrome extension store like so Manifesto
is a file that you add to your Chrome
extension when you ship it onto the
store you are perfectly allowed to
inject third party scripts in the sites
that people enter so when you as a user
install a extension on your browser that
extension is able to inject a script and
fortunately there are certain industries
that are really heavily targeted by
malware script and those are online
betting websites cryptocurrency
exchanges cryptocurrency sites in
general there are a lot of really nasty
plugins out there that try to steal all
sorts of information out of those so
this is another thing where I feel we
need to be a little more cautious it's
not CU something made it onto the Chrome
web store that it is safe the theme at
Google Chrome web or that manages this
they likely have some type of review
mechanisms in place in fact there's two
of them that they make public in their
Chrome web store but the reality is that
as soon as there's a third party script
in there they don't really know with any
level of certainty what they're actually
getting from these third parties because
the only thing that that third party
line of code in that script is is a
reference to another web server and
while you can check that web server
today you're not certain how it's going
to behave tomorrow and in fact what I'm
seeing can be different from what you're
seeing right and that's another element
here is the most aggressive attacks that
have happened of this type they last for
many weeks if not months and they lasted
that long because they were able to fly
below the radar by only injecting in a
certain percentage of users browsers in
specific regions under specific
circumstances and if you wrot that
rotate that every couple of hours and
you say for instance West Coast us gets
a bad script 1% of the time if they have
a certain user agent and you go to
another region you fly below the radar
for so long that even if people are
complaining about it on Twitter the
tread feed vendors will probably not add
it to their tread feed because they
cannot reproduce the attack that is a
major issue Dynamic of scripts in
general referring to a third-party
domain and trusting whatever you're
getting from there is just not great and
unfortunately there are some tools that
will only work if you do it that way and
that's where we have to come in and
provide Solutions so that at least when
you use these tools you are given some
level of security thank you for that
Simon
I was hoping and tell me we can do that
is just as an example take a site that
you might have investigated in the past
just to see how many and types of third
partyy javascripts it has you know you
made a point earlier on the show that a
lot of websites had the polyl even
though they may not have needed it
anymore so there are legitimate cases
where people have third party scripts
but also sounds like cases where you
know people just haven't taken the care
to remove stuff they don't need is it
possible do you have a example site that
we could check to see what kinds of
third party scripts it has yes so on our
own website you can enter the domain of
an website and it will go there we will
crawl it and unless they have bot
detection we will tell you what third
party scripts are on that page how many
there are we will crawl a few pages we
will tell you whether there are scripts
on different pages Etc I don't want to
name call anyone specific here but
there's a very large sport Sports
clothing e-commerce brand out there that
I think many of us have items from we
have over 120 of these on their website
and it's ranging from a range of
analytics tools some of which overlap in
functionality to as I said a chatbot or
captas or tags for certain social media
tools that are also scripts they are
using some special AI tracking
capability that helps them customize the
store for the types of things that you
have looked at in the past and your
other like tics that they have on you
120 of these fully Dynamic things is an
totally impossible number to manage
unless you have a tool for it I like to
refer to like it's basically babysitting
120 fully Dynamic babies that have not
had a nap and they're still kind of
Highly energetic in an noise you just
can't handle that many you can maybe
handle one or two of those by visiting
them regularly and making sure that
there's no suspicious behaviors like new
SSL certificates being issued for that
domain or changes of ownership of the
domain or code changes that look out of
line but I mean as soon as you have more
than maybe 10 it's entirely impossible
and and that is the reality if you go
around the web open the developer
console have a read through their head
tag look at the third party scripts that
are loaded also in the main of that page
you will see that there's a lot of them
and in fact modern Frameworks like
nextjs and like most single page web app
Frameworks they make this problem worse
because as you navigate through pages or
so it looks you're navigating through
pages the pages are not actually fully
being rendered so the previously present
third party scripts are still present on
the next page as youur so as a developer
if you make people rout to the payment
page do a hard refresh make sure that
that actually does a full like window
refresh and it's not just like changed
URL in the Navar that is like another
common thing that we see that there are
payment portals present on websites and
all of the other scripts from the other
pages are still there
even though if you manually refreshed on
the payment portal those scripts
wouldn't be there so at least somebody
knew about the problem but because of
how single page web apps work they are
still there so we know there are risks
and you mentioned data exfiltration
where data is sent over and maybe this
is the example of the payment where I
enter my credit card information and the
third party script sends that
information somewhere else right yes
that is kind of a very serious type of
attack here and to be clear this has
happened so often that the pcid assist
spec so the payment guard industry
specification that we all have to adhere
to for accepting payments online their
four generation which is kicking in
fully in effect in March next year they
require you to keep a list of these
third party scripts why they are there
and have tamper proofing in place to
keep an eye on them so as they change
that you are alerted so that is a very
specific type of third partyy script
attack that happens so often often to
the point that they like particularly
had to call it out in essentially
compliance and that has actually had an
interesting side effect when you get
Cyber insurance they will ask you about
your pcid assist status so if you go
through that form real quick and you say
yeah yeah yeah I'm fine and then some
incident happens and it turns out well
actually you haven't really lived up to
the spec of PCI DSS it could be that the
Cyber insurer just says Nope we can't
cover you here you've not actually taken
the responsibilities that you had to
take so then there you go it's
unfortunately a very common one that one
I will put a link I've noticed a blog
post on your website on this so I'll put
a link to that in the show
notes SC radio has an opening for a
volunteer host to produce five episodes
per year to apply please follow the
instructions on our website at se-
radio.net
cont what else beside data exfiltration
Al so you have data exilation of credit
cards users credentials you can mine
crypto in people's browsers browsers
have become more powerful and more
capable and we've added so many more new
cool features to it that we're using for
all types of legitimate reasons but
those can all be used for illegitimate
reasons as well so as people are
building Progressive web apps those
often store local data sensitive data
locally in a browser session well an
example there is that there are third
party scripts out there that look for
that sensitive information as soon as
you reconnect back to the internet would
upload that information so that type of
data exfiltration I would say is rather
new the mining crypto one kind of peaked
and has since come down a bit because
there are certain levers built into
Chrome now that would alert to an extent
but you can still stay below the
threshold so it's still kind of an issue
but then there's also other ones like
malicious redirect malicious rewrites on
pages I mean anything that can happen
within a browser really can be used to
an extent for malicious use logging you
out from all of your other sessions
unfortunately is also a thing you can
still pull off so logging people out to
just annoy them you can do that so as
you mentioned it's only a problem on you
know keeping track of how things are
changing but to begin with how can
developers decide if a script is good to
use is that the reputation and
reliability of the provider what should
they look for any red flags yes so
that's usually my first recommendation
is make sure that if you implement a
third- party script in your website that
this is a company that gets that that is
a major security risk and that they have
to protect that properly so don't trust
some random person on Twitter that made
some Analytics tool and this very early
in career and doesn't necessarily
Express that they get a security risk
that's a sort of thing that I wouldn't
really trust but then the next stage
that I tend to recommend to people is
try and create two buckets a bucket of
tools built by Act ual technology
companies people that get engineering
get how to write safe code and get the
importance of it and then a bucket of
companies that quote unquote we also
have a script right or can you add the
script real quick the issue there is
that those types of companies are
usually that's not their Core Business
and they tend to do a worse job at
protecting those and so those are the
ones that I would always seek to avoid
well then as a next step in that
framework I would say if you can self
host or there are two options and one is
one you can host and one is like a fully
Dynamic version then try and go towards
the one that you can self host because
that's the best way to deal with the
security risk unfortunately for some
tools that's just going to be impossible
or the static code that they give you to
self-host actually still refers to third
party things and third party
dependencies so be mindful of that and
then eventually and this is a sad
reality you are probably going to have
some Dynamic tools on your website so
taking into account the reputation of
those you should still likely use a tool
like ours and that's why we have that
free tier that's why we have a g
business tier so that you can actually
go ahead and just use it don't have to
worry about it and those third party
scripts that are Dynamic they're now
flowing through us so at least we're
keeping an eye on how they behave for
all of your user so if a user in Hawaii
at 4 P.M in the afternoon gets a
different script from what you've seen
on all of your other users well then at
least would' be able to alert you for
that and then of course the other things
that you can do that I always recommend
people to consider but in general are
bad developer experience use things like
content security policies to define the
domains that you want to allow to be
fetched by the browser of your user the
painful thing is that that that doesn't
actually solve a lot it only allows you
to define the sources it doesn't allow
you to define the payloads necessarily
so that doesn't solve the entire problem
and then in case scripts are actually
static then also adding that hash of
that script to the script de to Define
that that is the hash that should be
allowed and nothing else
you can still work your way around that
and Bad actors have historically found
ways to do that but that at least gives
you some level of certainty and security
is all about layering so you add a layer
you add a layer you make the risk
smaller and smaller and smaller until it
is a negligible risk and you can
demonstrate that you have done
everything to the furthest extent
possible that you can with the
technology available and then of course
there are just tools that make this
easier for you that's what we've built I
do want to talk a little bit more on the
browser security controls and content
security icies but before we do that is
there anything unique here with respect
to mobile it's interesting because
mobile browsers are slightly different
from desktop browsers but there are many
different browser engines out there
right chromium is definitely one that we
see most of the time but got web kit
being used Safari there's a whole bunch
of exotic ones and people building new
browsers which are generally things that
I support the reality is that we often
use browsers without actually realizing
that a progressive web app a web viw are
essentially browsers and they have the
full attack surface of a browser so when
it comes to the native security aspects
that you can use well a progressive web
app because it is essentially a browser
also supports things like content
security policies some things like web
view can but not always to the fullest
extent or the behavior is ever so
slightly off there isn't really much
more that you can do within a pwa or web
VI that you can't do in a browser
already because they are L just web apps
so but my advice towards people and I
always say like I don't really want to
give advice because this is a subject
very unfortunately there's a lot of
nuances but generally my advice towards
people is if you're using anything
that's a browser or pwa that really is
just a browser make sure that you have
as much control over your code as
possible and use the right tools and
understand that security is about
layering so use something like socket to
protect that open source dependency that
you load for npm that is the better
thing to do and then for the client side
fetch things there wasn't really a good
solution well that's what we went out
and build so back to you know managing
third party script dependencies you know
the one of the first things you said is
self-host if you can but then that gets
to be a problem because the JavaScript
could be having other calls to other
third parties can I ask a naive question
can't you just pull them and self host
the dependencies yourself you can but in
some cases say you can't so I'll give
you an example right so let's say you're
using intercom as a chatbot on your
website well of course someone typed
something into that chat bot that data
gets sent somewhere then you correspond
with that person through a fancy
dashboard and then they get a message
back well these are Dynamic behaviors
right and that must be dynamic so some
of these scripts you simply cannot
self-host in their entirety and that is
for analytics and chat Bots and captas
and ads and third party video loaders
and all of these types of things they
are inherently Dynamic that's their
functionality there isn't really a good
workaround for that luckily some of
these tools they have like service side
rendered versions available or some of
them have sort of middleware version
available where if you're using xjs you
can do some of these things in like
Cloud workers basically sitting in the
middle the reality is that they can pull
off a lot of these same malicious acts
over there so the attack surface is just
slightly moved to another area that
you're not protecting and that's a major
issue so you simply can't always it
would be lovely if we could but then we
are back to a world where we don't
really have much Dynamic this of course
if you built your own chat B into your
website you actually like own the whole
package where you found an open- Source
thing that you can self host yourself
yeah that would be amazing but when I
built my own business that was the first
thing I realized doesn't scale because
self-hosting these types of things
versus just paying somebody to maintain
it for you you can't open source
everything and then have to maintain it
and deal with it yourself sometimes you
got to actually pay somebody to do a
better job right so there is no Brute
Force approach you do need to figure out
how to yeah handle third party scripts
back to browser security controls you
mentioned content security policies can
you drill a little bit more into that
and what else is there so content
security policies are basically a header
you add to your web page when you are
the web developer of a page and in there
you've got I think a little over 30
different directives you can add and
that's anything from like connect source
to script source to adding things like
specifying for instance that certain
fonts are allowed to be loaded but not
from certain sources Etc you can go
quite far into detail about it there's a
lot of things you can write there and
it's all in a Mozilla documentation so
you can like drill your way into that
and see it and also you can add logging
endpoints so for instance if something
breaks a certain rule then you could
receive a lock for that con security
policies are currently going to their
sort of third major wave in existence so
csp3 is around the corner and so in csp2
there were certain limitations that made
it hard to love I mean so for instance
you could actually report back the first
50 digits of a third party script so
that at least you could verify some of
the payload but then of course guess
what Bad actors did they just made sure
that whatever bad thing they changed
didn't show in the first 50 characters
of a script it's csp3 there is a deeper
specification towards like hashes and
those types of things but in csp3 there
are still certain limitations that I
personally find it making a sub optimal
thing to use so ultimately it still
comes down to the same problem CSP
policies Define third-party paths
thirdparty scripts as in the Ser the
actual URLs that you're calling but they
don't do much with the payload aside
from adding a hash which by the way you
could have added to the script tag
itself anyway so that's one of those
controls there are other controls but I
would say CSP is sort of the major one
that is used for client side Security
today and over time hopefully more of
these get added as I mentioned there are
just more functionality being added to
browsers every day and as a result of
that we also should be looking for ways
to secure these things as I mentioned
adding more things that allow you to
store sensitive information in the
browser of users examples for that
instance index DB but also wesm or
allows you to do basically virtual
machines in browsers or checking
containers in browsers to an extent
there's just a lot you can do there and
those things need security as well so on
the CSP you mentioned that you can limit
the sources that you're pulling the
script from what happens though if your
script that you're pulling is now
referring to other sources how do you
even know what you should be limiting so
that's where that loging capability is
so useful so there's a report only
directive with in CSP that basically you
can just add to any type of CSP header
you added or at least most of them
support the report only header and what
it does it just literally sends little
packages to an endpoint and you can then
read into those packages and you can get
a list of those third party scripts that
were being loaded and as you mentioned
indeed if a script calls another script
and that script calls another script
you're working your way down that list
all of those will be listed in CSP then
you of course now have a list that is
current today but that is again sort of
the reason why people don't tend to like
CSP policies very much if these scripts
change and they add another URL to that
script or another dependency and you
haven't updated your CSP policies that's
going to result in it breaking because
that dependency is not going to be
loaded and that I think is a good
indicator of why content security
policies haven't really reached
widescale adoption because as soon as
you're like using it and you're actually
defining things to the level of
strictness that it should be then as
soon as you do that then it's just a
matter of time before or certain third
party tools are going to break and the
reality is that the people that
Implement these third party scripts
they're often not actually the ones that
chose them or use them it's often
another department within a company it's
somebody in marketing that asked about
an analytic script or somebody in
support that said we use this tool now
or somebody in legal saying we now need
to add a cookie ban or there are so many
of these scripts the engineers are not
the ones that use them or chose them and
they are somehow the people that like
have to go to their laptop if they start
doing weird stuff for their CSP policy
breaks and that just makes for bad user
experiences so there have been kind of
suboptimal attempts at closing this risk
down but the reality is that the risk
itself is also something that a lot of
good tools kind of like thrive on that
Dynamic allows you to quickly ship
improvements to your tool add new
features to your tools and that Dynamic
and allows you to do great things but as
I mentioned that is also kind of the
dark problem about this and so CSP
doesn't really address that issue mhm so
CSV is more like better broken than
insecure in a sense I think the risk is
mostly that you're just going to
eventually have an issue eventually
you're going to have a script breaking
and also your local development
experience may be worse right because
you're using an actual like production
you may be referring to certain third
party scripts locally when you're doing
your local testing you might be using
some extension that also Lo loads a
script your behaviors are going to be
different and by the way if you start
looking at content security policies on
big websites you will funny things
people referring to Google tag
manager.com with a wild card which is
essentially bypassing the whole point of
CSP because anybody can host something
on Google tag manager so it doesn't
quite solve anything really I mean the
reason why people add those wild card is
because there's also limits to the
length of the header so if you have 50
scripts on your website you probably
can't reference all of them in their
full URL format so you start adding wild
cards to it and as you add a wild card
you open up to bigger problems so
content security policies are a bit of
headache and luckily there are tools
that make it easier to manage them but
they are not going to solve really most
of these attacks and they are just a bit
of a cumbersome thing to you so there
must be something better is what we
thought and then we went ahead and tried
and build it what about sandboxing and
you know the third party scripts would
that help with some of the example an
example you had earlier where you know
unless you refresh the page for the
where you enter payment method you still
have third party scripts that have no
business being on that page the thing is
that requests make for different
responses and as a result the answer to
this is it depends so if I make a
request from my laptop using a certain
user agent on a certain website a
certain time of the day using my IP
address that's going to give a certain
result and that result could be the same
if I'm going to that from a Sandbox
environment hosted on AWS but that could
also be different right and so what
we've seen is that scripts behave
differently as soon as you're a security
company and you're using an easily
differentiable like way of doing a
request so I'll give you an example if
you're using a tool that crawls a bunch
of websites from AWS IP address or from
an actual residential IP address you'll
see different behaviors it's the same
with these third party scripts so if a
bad actor were to see a request being
made from AWS or gcp or any large cloud
provider that security vendors use then
it is incredibly likely that they would
give you a bad version of the script
usually these attackers they have a
clean script and they have a sort of
quote unquote dirty script the one that
has the bad code in it and the bad code
is reserved for people that they know
are going to be actual humans using
urtic are actual like normal humans and
as soon as they see an automated request
or a request coming from a cloud
provider they would either just four or
four not serve anything or they would
simply yeah give the clean version of
the script so that is approach that I've
seen honestly give more false security
than real security there are examples of
attacks that are incredibly dumb that
you can just detect that way but the
reality is that a bad actor that is
really targeted they would be able to
deal with that very easily so sandbox
for third party scripts I don't think is
necessarily the right way sorry maybe I
didn't quite pose my question properly
or didn't fully understand your response
what I was trying to understand was is
there a way on my web page as a you know
the website or could I limit the access
the third party scripts have by putting
them in an if frame or something yes
definitely so you can use iframes the
behavior of that is rather well defined
and rather consistent across the
browsers so you can Define more
specifically like what type of things
that it's able to do and try and limit
access that is definitely something you
can try to do however some of these
scripts don't like that right I'll give
you an example for instance the stri
third party script that you use on your
website when you add stripe it has to be
deployed globally on your website if you
don't then they will shout at you if you
try to proxy that script by the way they
will also shout at you if you try to
self-host it they will shout at you so
there are things you can try and do if
you're very creative I personally have
not seen that being implemented on
almost any web page even very like
well-known good security people they get
caught like by these third party scripts
they don't do these more exotic security
tricks so the answer to it is probably
you could but it at that point becomes a
harder thing to manage over time I'll
give you another example there was a
script that we were able to proxy for
some time and all of a sudden it changed
and it started causing some issues right
we have built a whole pipeline to then
stop proxying and do something different
with it to still keep an eye on it but
the reality is that that happens because
these are Dynamic and so it could work
today could stop working tomorrow and
you now have another thing on your
website you have to keep an eye on what
do modern web Frameworks help with any
of this you know maybe react angular is
there any help they provide developers
in securing third party scripts not
really on the framework level I would
say so Progressive web apps I think are
a good example of how this problem
became more hidden and is still very
relevant and then single page web app
Frameworks they actually do cause this
issue to be more severe here because
when you navigate from page to page
because it is a single page web it
doesn't actually fully rerender the page
and those third partyy scripts remain on
that page so you can navigate on an
e-commerce website from the homepage and
select an item and add it to the cart
and make it to the payment portal and
your browser never actually did a full
refresh and therefore all these third
party scripts are still there it would
be awesome if in Frameworks they were
more conscious of sensitive data fields
and as soon as there are certain SC
scripts present or certain actions
present within a page that it would
trigger a hard refresh for you but today
we rely on the engineers to manually
make that happen so when people navigate
to the SL payments page that it does
actually do a full rerender of the page
instead of that like service sorry the
client side reender of a page it should
be a full refresh so you know it sounds
like it's only hard to do but there are
a series of best practices that
developers should follow regardless
right at least
take care of the things you know about
in the category of monitoring and
keeping up with changes what are some of
these best practices for monitoring the
scripts the thing that I like like did
in the past was the most commonly used
scripts I would have a little Lambda
function for them to call them and I
would create a hash and as soon as the
hash would change I would have a quick
look at it usually these scripts are
opusc or minified so they're harder to
read but you can Dem Minify or decate
them and that's a legitimate reason to
the office gate for security analysis
every now and then you can have a read
through them in the previous elaboration
you just talked about adding a Lambda
function for hash to the JavaScript so
that you know when it changes I've also
heard of something similar that browses
support but not necessarily in the same
way sub resource Integrity can you
explain what that is sure so I refer to
it a few times in other sections of this
podcast but if you add a script to your
website or a link or any type of third
party resource it's actually a directive
that is widely supported for various
tags you can add a hash of that third
party object resource to the fetch
object that you use and so that allows
you to basically say if anything doesn't
match this hash don't like render it
don't run it don't execute it and that's
incredibly helpful for dealing with
static resources so if something is
hosted on a CDN and it shouldn't change
then you definitely should add that like
hash to that script source
however we notice that it isn't as
widely adopted by people there's a few
reasons why so first things first is
sometimes hashes are used that create a
false sense of security and are actually
bypassable for instance an md5 hash you
can generate bad codes into good code
and then obis skate in a certain way so
it matches the same hash that is
possible but then mostly and this is the
most common problem we see is if you
actually use a script that does change
over time and you added a hash to that
script well then of course what's going
to happen is as soon as it changes it
would get blocked it wouldn't render and
that incident in general happens a lot
for people and as a result they don't
use the sub resource Integrity as much
which is sad because it is a useful
thing so in general we do tend to
recommend people when they use an actual
static thing that hasn't changed in a
certain amount of time just to gash it
and then also you can self host it and
add that Sur resource Integrity header
to the object you mentioned CDN do CDN
have to do something special to support
this like my first thought was if the
script does change shouldn't it become a
different resource yeah and then the
hash would not match at that point so I
mean a CDN really shouldn't allow this
thing to be dynamic so I'll give you an
example for instance if you use cdnjs
which is hosted on the cloud flare
Network you actually get the hashes in
the web page right so you should be able
to use that well of course in the CDN
provider should make sure that those
objects never change there was actually
an incident a few years ago where the
cdnjs release pipeline had a breach in
it and luckily nobody found out except
for a whad hacker that then flagged it
through a bug Bounty program but that
could have added some real issues right
because that provider if people didn't
Implement that hash on the script Source
they like yeah they could have added to
a massive supply chain Tech so in
general CDN providers should just make
sure that whatever they host is well
protected static and probably have some
controls in place himself to make sure
that that remains the way I think it
becomes a more serious issue if these
scripts start calling new third party
dependencies I tend to have a manual
look at those anyway so those are things
you can do I think the the risk of a
script doing something bad without a new
third-party domain added to the script
it's smaller I mean it isn't always easy
to detect because sometimes they're like
B 64 encoded but as soon as I see that
there's like a third party script added
to a script or a new third party
endpoint to send data to or new post
request being sent to new domain
that's when I tend to have a look at
scripts ourselves manually that's what I
did in the past our tool now does that
for us we use AI to pass through these
types of changes through the entire code
and then as a result we're basically
able to automate some of these
detections some of these I would say the
majority of these detections we actually
have automated now so Seaside as a
product is kind of the manual review
process that I used to do as a PM
building similar products let's talk
about that a little bit more you
mentioned using AI can you elaborate
like how do you do that how do you train
how does that actually work so it's
pretty cool how there's a lot of cyber
security companies out there now that
are basically taking the Securities
analyst tasks and automate them and use
AI to deal with the obscurity of that
job and we have basically built that in
for our use case so because we have full
access to the actual payload of a script
we need to review that we of course have
a range of static detections on top of
that we look at things in changes over
time but then we also use readily
available llms that we have either made
small like changes to or we are using
the stock version to to analyze these
scripts again using specific prompts and
the results of that are surprisingly
good humans of course read JavaScript
but as soon as it becomes a very large
file our success rate starts to drop and
that is also something that like we got
to recognize that we are not that great
at that sometimes we get more consistent
results today using some of these modern
llms and they improve pretty much every
week every time there's a new one we try
it out those are able to explain to us
what these scripts do how they have
changed compared to a previous version
of it I don't want to go too deep into
our detection capabilities but the llms
are pretty decent at going through
third-party javascripts especially if we
give them the unop fiscated versions of
it the Dem minified versions of it and
then figuring out whether something
looks a little weird whether it requires
further review and then we go from there
so could someone sign up to Seaside to
just try this review capability yeah so
currently the free tier is not going
into a lot of detail on how we detected
such something is potentially malicious
we tend to just take action on your
behalf the great thing is that these
third party scripts when they go bad we
obviously also want to make sure that
more people are protected against them
so for large attacks like the polyfill
one we do blog posts and we want to make
clear how these things have happened and
we will probably talk talk about them in
places like this so that's currently the
best thing we can do for our free tier
users as of course when we open up too
much the risks are that people will
reverse engineer detection capabilities
and try to bypass them that way so the
free tier is I would say a good way of
not having to worry too much about it
but it's not giving you a lot of detail
which will probably mean that at some
point you want more detail and that's
where the business and Enterprise
versions give you a lot more context and
also more ability to Define lists block
things allow certain behaviors allow
certain data extractions Define that
list of scripts you want to allow on the
payment portal to comply with pcid
assist those types of things are then
part of the other tiers I find it
incredibly important that today we move
security from an Enterprise only
business to a more accessible business
because web security shouldn't be
Enterprise only and that's why we have
that free tier that's why we have that
rather affordable business tier it's
currently priced at about $100 a month
that is there so that people with a neat
podcast website or a good personal blog
or a side project e-commerce store where
they sell socks with a picture of your
dog on them that they can at least be
sure that they have their security
covered and that is something that we
try to do well regardless I personally
think that that's sort of the most
rewarding thing about what we're doing
the fact that we're taking web security
and we're making it more accessible to
people because in all like we're really
realistic about it if you have a couple
CP of hundred dollars to spend on web
security there aren't that many vendors
that you can go to we want to make that
easier you been talking about a proxy
why a proxy and you know my first
concern would be as a user doesn't it
cause latency I love that question that
was a very obvious objection that we had
to deal with from like the early stages
of design even so we decided on the
proxy approach because it gives us the
most certainty that the data we're
seeing is the one that the user is
actually getting as soon as a subsequent
request has to happen from different
infrastructure we do not know whether
that is really what the user got of
course you can use hashes and all of
that stuff but as soon as it doesn't
match it's harder to find the match so
the proxy approach was the more
laborsome hard thing to build but the
right thing to build and the way that we
countered the performance implications
because you are right inherently if you
add a thing to the flow of a request
it's likely going to add a delay but we
counter that by doing some clever
engineering so when scripts are allowing
to be cached our cache control header
defines it's allowed to be cached then
of course we cach them and those scripts
are being cached directly in memory on
some of our Edge locations CDN have to
support large file sizes and as a result
they have a more complex data storage
architecture and as a result it can be a
little bit slower we don't have that
because scripts are usually not that
large and then on top of that our CDN
that we provide for thirdparty scripts
only do thirdparty Scripts that means we
don't have to have 50 different
mechanisms living in front of them doing
all types of other things and as a
result in a real world example that I
like to refer to is when you use a
certain script I'm not going to call out
which one from my flat in London it
would take 78 milliseconds to fetch that
from its actual Source if you fetch it
through Seaside it only takes 48
milliseconds the great thing here is
there's a few things that also matter
the fact is that a lot of these third
party scripts are being fetched
asynchronously so the latency wouldn't
even matter nobody would see it nobody
would notice it and then the other
aspect here is that as a proxy if all
these third party scripts come through
us we can actually handle on a
networking level these requests more
efficiently making these proxies even
able to basically offset their entire
latency just by doing that so taking
these requests and basically bundling
them and all those things combined lead
to static scripts being served 30 to 40%
faster fully Dynamic scripts being
served about 10 20 milliseconds slower
but if you have 50 scripts on your
website and we can make 30 of them
faster those 20 other ones are not going
to matter they're going to be offset and
especially if those are asynchronously
fetched so the latest C element we were
able to basically counter as efficiently
as we probably can today with technology
that's available and Technology like hp3
is actually making it more efficient to
do these things as well so that's
another thing all of these third party
scripts come from different servers they
don't necessarily support things like
htb3 htb2 Etc we can actually do that
for them through that proxy that we have
and that also makes for better
performance so yeah that in more depth
basically explains that performance
aspect I know it's a highly sensitive
part so that's why we talk about it but
it's not really the core reason why we
do what we do did I understand correctly
that there's two ways one is the proxy
and the other one is perhaps you know I
can use your review capabilities maybe
multiple times a day just to keep
checking my scripts is that fair or is
that only one path so we are really only
available as a proxy and that is because
that's the best way to deal with this
issue to give you that example of that
poly attack if you were to crawl that
script from a certain endpoint you would
have not been able to spot the attack
because the attack only injected the
malicious script if the user agent was a
certain mobile device browser in a
certain
geography so the only real way that
we're able to give you any level of
certainty is by actually being part of
the flow of the request hence that proxy
service and I find it important that we
don't don't give people a false sense of
security the proxying is the best thing
to do the every now and then screening
approach is a bit of a hack and doesn't
necessarily give you any level of
certainty and as a security company
people come to us to get the highest
level of of certainty that we can
provide so the crawler based approach we
are not that enthusiastically like
positioning at all but of course we do
do some of that just to train our own
detection capabilities and come ahead of
like new attacks that we haven't seen on
our own customers websites yet we don't
tend to productize that I don't think
that's what what you want to do because
as I said it is a it can easily create a
false sense of security and that doesn't
tend to help any situation so how do you
secure your scripts that's a good
question well we have third party
scripts on our own website and of course
we dog food our own product so we see a
lot of these things behave differently
over time not necessarily maliciously
and so that's currently the one of the
ways that we tend to improve our
detection capabilities is we have a
whole bunch of websites with a whole lot
of scripts on them we tend to look for
scripts on the web on other websites we
then have a look at how they work but
for our own website we are using our own
product funny enough in the free tier
currently because that's what works best
with got to stability and that business
and Enterprise version we're still
working on so I'd say over time we'll
probably put ourselves as an Enterprise
customer but currently we are just still
a free tier customer using our own
product I guess my question wasn't
necess limited to Third paries scripts
but in general like how do I trust that
your script is actually going to do what
it's supposed to do of course well so
our script of course as we are a
security company we make sure that we
take all the steps that we can take so
our infrastructure is secure audited
we're going through so to audit right
now make sure that none of the code gets
written can actually make it into that
main branch without a secondary review
our infrastructure is fully protected
using commonly used things on AWS or
proxy secure so like we we've basically
gone through the first extent possible
to make sure that our own script and our
own proxy is safe and we've even got
fallback mechanisms built into that
tamper proofing tamper detections Etc so
we've gone quite far even to the level
where the domain name that we use well
that is still Seaside of Dev is a domain
name that we we've done everything we
could to make sure will remain ours for
as long as you could possibly can funny
enough there are companies out there
that allow you to basically have actual
human verification you have to walk into
an office and show your passport to make
a name server change we haven't quite
like reached that level but at some
point we will so we've gone through the
furthest extent possible to secure our
own script our own proxy and that I
think is something that I mean we as a
security company can give you a better
sense of security than other third party
scripts that aren't security
products of course our own dependency
management we use a whole range of
products for I mentioned socket in this
call of course I love their product I
use their product there are other tools
out there that we also use I think as
most security companies and most well in
general companies do we don't tend to
talk too much about all the security
products we have internally because that
would allow people to try and bypass
some of them but yeah we're layered and
of the amount of money we' have raised a
good amount of that money is being spent
on making sure that we are safe and
everybody is properly trained that we
know what to look for and in case
something bad happens that we are the
first ones to know and that our
customers are not impacted using
multiple environments Etc thank you
Simon any topic you think we did not
cover that you'd like to talk about I
feel like we've done a rather
comprehensive review of all of the the
issues with it the potential risk there
are I think that was pretty
comprehensive yeah I think that was it
really from my side Simon how can people
contact you so the best way for people
getting contact with me is by going to
our website C site. Dev and go to the
contact Section there CU that will just
end up in my mailbox you can try and
send me a message over LinkedIn or
Twitter but I'm pretty bad at responding
at those sometimes so probably the best
bet to just go to our contact page thank
you so much I hope our listeners learn
from this and start to recognize that
this is a real problem that they should
keep an eye out thank you very
much thanks for listening to SC radio an
educational program brought to you by It
software magazine for more about the
podcast including other episodes visit
our website at se -
radio.net to provide feedback you can
comment on each episode on the website
or reach us on LinkedIn Facebook Twitter
or through our slack Channel at
seo. slack.com you can also email us at
team-
radio.net this and all other episodes of
SC radio is licensed under creative
commment license
2.5 thanks for listening